<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Chris Bracken</title>
    <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Chris Bracken</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chris.bracken.jp/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bonjour, Bon Vespre!</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2005/05/bonjour-bon-vespre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2005/05/bonjour-bon-vespre/</guid>
      <description>Just how far can you travel in a week and a half? It turns out pretty far. Combining planes, trains, ships, and automobiles, Yasuko and I travelled, all told, roughly 22,100 km over the Golden Week holiday.
From Tokyo to Avignon, on to Marseille, then Arles and Nîmes, followed by Carcassonne, Perpignan, and Barcelona, before heading back to Paris and home to Tokyo in 12 days wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad… Especially considering the car was a Fiat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York, NY, USA</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2004/09/new-york-ny-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2004/09/new-york-ny-usa/</guid>
      <description>Flew out to New York for interviews with Tokyo via videoconference on the 9th and 10th. More details later, but I’ll post pictures now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2004 in Japan</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2004/08/summer-2004-in-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2004/08/summer-2004-in-japan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had originally planned my summer vacations for May, then July, and finally,
in an effort to match my summer vacations with those of friends in Japan, ended
up shuffling them back to August. Aside from the scorching heat, August is a
fantastic time of year to visit. The heat this summer was more than a little
bit scorching though, it was the hottest summer in ten years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biking Japan 2003</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2003/08/biking-japan-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2003/08/biking-japan-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://chris.bracken.jp/post/2003-08-17-cycling-in-japan.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Brodie bike parked beside vending machines in front of restaurant&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan was to travel from Osaka north to the Japan Sea, northeast along the
coast to Joetsu, south through the alps to Nagano, then southeast all the way
to Tokyo — a total distance of close to 1200 km, entirely by bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in Canada</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2002/05/back-in-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2002/05/back-in-canada/</guid>
      <description>Back in Victoria, B.C. after a two month return home to Canada by land beginning in Mérida, Yucatán and continuing through Cuba, Belize, Guatemala, Honduras, then all the way back up through Guatemala, México, the U.S. and finally across Western Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chetumal, Quintana Roo, México</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2002/04/chetumal-quintana-roo-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2002/04/chetumal-quintana-roo-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we stepped off the Cubana Ilyushin Il-62 plane at the Cancun airport, I
literally kissed the ground in happiness. The airport was crowded with people
snacking on good Mexican food and the sound of shouting and laughter filled the
air. After all the episodes of trouble, dengue fever, and trying to figure out
what the hell was actually going on, it was easy to lose sight of just how
great a country México is, and after Cuba, coming back to México felt like
coming home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trinidad, Sancti Spiritus, Cuba</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2002/03/trinidad-sancti-spiritus-cuba/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2002/03/trinidad-sancti-spiritus-cuba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking down on the ocean from the rolling hills a kilometre away, Trinidad is
a small, traditional town whose population of 50,000 takes great pride in its
home. Founded by Diego Velásquez in 1514, Trinidad became a stopover for
explorers and trading ships travelling to and from México. During the 17th and
18th centuries, its economy largely depended on trading contraband with
pirates. The buildings are in incredibly good shape for their age, most of
which are at least two centuries old. It’s not too tough to see why Trinidad is
now a UNESCO World Heritage Site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Habana, Cuba</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2002/03/la-habana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2002/03/la-habana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Havana is a city of contradictions. It’s simultaneously one of the most
beautiful and most run down cities in the world. It’s hard to imagine how
things could be any worse, or any better given the Cuba’s political past and
present.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valladolid, Yucatán, México</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/12/valladolid-yucatan-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/12/valladolid-yucatan-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1543, Francisco de Montejo (the nephew of Mérida’s famous Francisco de
Montejo) descended on the ceremonial centre of the Zací (Hawk) Maya, waging war
on the &lt;em&gt;Cupules&lt;/em&gt;, a group of Maya that hadn’t taken kindly to the Spanish
conquistadors. When the battle was done and the town had been razed, he renamed
it Valladolid in honour of the Spanish city of the same name.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chichen Itzá, Yucatán, México</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/12/chichen-itza-yucatan-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/12/chichen-itza-yucatan-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Somewhere on the old highway between Cancún and Mérida lies Chichen Itzá. The
ruins at this site cover over 15 square kilometres, with &lt;em&gt;El Castillo&lt;/em&gt; alone
taking up 0.4 hectares. At 83 metres in length, the Ball Court is the largest
in Meso-America. The close proximity of the ruins to Cancún and the size of
some of the structures have made these the most famous Mayan ruins in the
country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tulúm, Quintana Roo, México</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/12/tulum-quintana-roo-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/12/tulum-quintana-roo-mexico/</guid>
      <description>Between San Cristóbal and Tulúm is a long, empty road. The overnight bus works beautifully for this trip, winding its way through the mountains, jungle and the vast plains of the Yucatán. The only major stop along the way is Escarcega, Campeche. By major, I mean a couple of comida corrida places, a papaya tree, and a dusty bus stop on a long, empty stretch of highway. By six in the morning, we were in Tulúm, a slightly bigger collection of restaurants and bus stops along a long, empty stretch of highway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Cristóbal de las Casas, Chiapas, México</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/12/san-cristobal-de-las-casas-chiapas-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/12/san-cristobal-de-las-casas-chiapas-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;San Cristóbal is, without question, one of the most beautiful towns in Mexico.
It’s also the ideal temperature for visiting Canadians, with the temperature
hovering around 10 °C, and the humidity close to 100% during the daytime in
winter. It’s cold, damp and cloudy. After months of scorching heat and
humidity, I was in heaven. San Cristóbal makes an ideal base from which to do
day-trips to the surrounding villages of San Juan Chamula and
Zinacantán—indigenous villages comprising the Tzotzil and Tzeltal indigenous
groups respectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palenque, Chiapas, México</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/12/palenque-chiapas-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/12/palenque-chiapas-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Christmas, we decided to take a trip to the state of Chiapas, about an 8
hour bus ride from Mérida. Although Chiapas has been a somewhat politically
unstable state during the past 10 years, it is also home to some of the most
incredible scenery, archaeological sites and indigenous culture in the
country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dzibilchaltún, Yucatán, México</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/09/dzibilchaltun-yucatan-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/09/dzibilchaltun-yucatan-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About halfway between Mérida and Progresso lie the ruins of Dzibilchaltún, an
important centre in the ancient world of the Maya. The name means &amp;lsquo;The place
with writing on the stones.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isla Mujeres, Quintana Roo, México</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/09/isla-mujeres-quintana-roo-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/09/isla-mujeres-quintana-roo-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://chris.bracken.jp/post/2001-09-06-lancha.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;A small &amp;#39;lancha&amp;#39; boat floats in the crystal-clear blue waters of the Caribbean, moored a few metres offshore a white sandy beach.&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lo que tu eres, yo fui&lt;br&gt;
Lo que yo soy, luego serás&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;—Inscription on the pirate Mundaca’s Tomb&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chelem, Yucatán, México</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/08/chelem-yucatan-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2001 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/08/chelem-yucatan-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grabbed a bus north to Progreso to go to the beach. While it was beautiful
weather and the ocean looked great, there were no palm trees on the beach, so
it was impossible to find any shade. We’d heard that in the next town over,
Yucalpetén, there were some great beaches, so we asked around and finally found
a colectivo headed out in that direction. The one we found stopped
by a bathing centre and the town of Chelem. Now right now I’m going to come
straight out and say it: if someone ever tells you a story about the amazing
beaches at Yucalpetén, just back away slowly and do not make any sudden
moves—the person you are talking to has probably escaped from an asylum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progreso, Yucatán, México</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/08/progreso-yucatan-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2001 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/08/progreso-yucatan-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Half an hour north of Mérida is the port town of Progreso. Though it’s on the
gulf side of the peninsula, the water is still a beautiful turquoise-blue; it
puts Canadian beaches to shame. On a hot weekend, Progreso makes a fun day
trip. The wind keeps you cool, and as long as you keep ordering drinks, the
food comes free at the palapa huts on the beach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Izamal, Yucatán, México</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/08/izamal-yucatan-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/08/izamal-yucatan-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Took a trip a few towns to the east this morning, to Izamal. While Mérida is
known throughout México as the White City, Izamal is referred to as the Yellow
City due to the preponderance of yellow buildings. With a population of 15,000
or so, it’s much quieter than Mérida, and horse-drawn carriages are still used
as transportation by some of its residents. The two big tourist attractions
here are the ruins of Kinich-Kakmó, one of 12 Mayan temples that originally
stood at the site of this town, and the Franciscan Monastery, one of the first
in the New World, built from the stones of the largest Mayan temple in Izamal
after it was torn down by the Conquistadors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quest for a Hammock</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/08/quest-for-a-hammock/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/08/quest-for-a-hammock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://chris.bracken.jp/post/2001-08-28-old-door.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;A worn-down wooden door lies framed by a crumbling building façade in Mérida. Traces of faded lettering remain where the paint has not flaked away.&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Mérida, most people sleep in hammocks. Walk down any residential street and
look in the windows and you’ll see hammocks strung all over the room. What I’m
getting at is that I finally caved in and bought a hammock. Now sit back and
listen, ’cause here’s my advice…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mérida, Yucatán, México</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/08/merida-yucatan-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2001 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/08/merida-yucatan-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arrived in Cancún on Friday at about 6 pm, took out some money from the bank
machine, and hopped into a colectivo¹ for Ciudad Cancún—the city itself—a
twenty minute drive from the long strip of hotels between the lagoon and the
ocean that the outside world refers to as Cancún. By the time the colectivo got
to the bus station, it was 9 pm, so after checking out the schedule and booking
tickets, there was just enough time to grab some dinner and get some sleep
before heading off to Mérida first thing the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¡Hola México!</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/08/hola-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2001 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2001/08/hola-mexico/</guid>
      <description>After a year and a half in San Francisco, California, we’ve moved to Mérida, Yucatán, México. So far so good! The heat is scorching, the humidity is sweltering, and the mosquitos are biting. But Mérida is a beautiful city, and the people are wonderful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
