<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Canada on Chris Bracken</title>
    <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/tags/canada/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Canada on Chris Bracken</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chris.bracken.jp/tags/canada/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to the US: Importing a Canadian Vehicle</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2011/05/moving-to-us-letter-of-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2011/05/moving-to-us-letter-of-compliance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A big difference between the last time I moved to the US and this time is that
this time, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a lot more stuff. One of those things is a recent-vintage
Nissan. Faced with the prospect of selling my car and buying a new one, I chose
instead to import the one I know and love. Here is my story. But be
forewarned, it is not for the faint of heart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy 139th Birthday!</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2006/07/happy-139th-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2006/07/happy-139th-birthday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Canadians in Tokyo got a head start on the Canada Day celebrations, kicking
things off at 8:30 am with a pancake breakfast at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.maplesportsbar.jp/&#34;&gt;Maple Leaf Bar &amp;amp;
Grill&lt;/a&gt;, followed by a Canada Day barbeque at Yoyogi Park including
hot dogs, yakitori, a massive Canadian Flag cake, and imported Canadian beer.
By 6pm things, as started to wind down at the park, people started the long
trek back to Shibuya and into the Maple Leaf, where it was standing room
only.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Medical Research</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2006/06/canadian-medical-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2006/06/canadian-medical-research/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t let anyone tell you that Canada never contributed groundbreaking research to the medical field. First, the discovery and isolation of insulin by researchers at the University of Toronto; now this paper published in the British Medical Journal, co-authored by a Grade 8 student from Hamilton, Ontario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End of Season</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2004/04/end-of-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2004/04/end-of-season/</guid>
      <description>Two last ski trips for the year. The first, at Mt. Washington, saw a beautiful attempt at a forward flip by Kevin, and Pippa ripping it up. For the second, I burned off on the 10 hour trek to Nelson, where Trav skiied until he dropped and I tried out the new Rossignol B2s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt. Washington</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2004/03/mt-washington/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2004/03/mt-washington/</guid>
      <description>Put a group of idiots together on skis and boards, and you’ve got a guaranteed recipe for a good time. Tom managed a sweet 360 and Matt successfully pulled off half a backflip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am Canadian</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2003/02/i-am-canadian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2003/02/i-am-canadian/</guid>
      <description>Since the original I am Canadian ad, Molson has released a slew of others, but until recently, I haven’t been too impressed; however, the I Am Canadian Anthem is a hilarious 90-second snapshot of the cultural history of this country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in Canada</title>
      <link>https://chris.bracken.jp/2002/05/back-in-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris.bracken.jp/2002/05/back-in-canada/</guid>
      <description>Back in Victoria, B.C. after a two month return home to Canada by land beginning in Mérida, Yucatán and continuing through Cuba, Belize, Guatemala, Honduras, then all the way back up through Guatemala, México, the U.S. and finally across Western Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>